Hey, everybody. Welcome
to the content video
going over section 9.3 of your textbook.
I know it says text file processing,
but really we're going to
be talking about files with
open. So the with open statement.
So in the last content video,
we talked about files and how to
use the open function to open a
file, read it, write to it, and
append. And the with statement
kind of simplifies all of that.
And it makes it a lot
easier to open files. So
we're just going to jump
right over into some
examples, because I think
it'll help make more sense.
Okay, so like I said, we have
covered how to open a file with open.
One thing that I failed to mention,
let's make a file, we'll call it
output.txt. if we create or if I was
to do something like this file equals
open output.txt I will get a file
not found error and this is a really
common error if you're looking for
something and you have not pointed
your file path to the right
location you'll get a file not found
error. Now I want to create a file
in my week 5 directory here so I'm
actually going to copy the path of
my week 5 directory and paste it in
before my output.txt see how it
gave me up to week five but then it
concatenated my strings here so I'm
actually going to add a forward slash
there between them and since this
file doesn't exist what I'm going to
do is I'm actually going to open it
in write mode and write mode will
create the file for me so I ran that
and now check out what's over here
in my directory is output.txt so
that's really cool okay and then we
talked about how you can write to
the file and close it. But I'm just
going to close it right now. I don't
know. Maybe I'll file.write, spell.
And then we'll file.close. OK.
So withOpen operates kind
of like an if statement.
So with open allows you to
open a file and do all the
logic on it within the
scope of the with statement.
And then the file will by
default close once the with
statement is over. So let
me show you what I mean. So
let's say with open, let's
paste in that file path
again. And then this time I'm
going to say output 2.ext,
close this in quotation
marks because it didn't.
I'll open this file in write mode
again because the file doesn't
currently exist and then the with
statement needs I don't know if I
would call this a qualifier or just
another another bit to it called
as and then you define your variable
name that you want your file
saved to in the with statement
so I'll call this file to add a
colon at the end and then notice
how when I hit enter, my next line
of code was automatically indented.
So I'll say file2.write, hello,
throw a new line in there,
file2.write,
goodbye,
throw another new line in there.
And then I can just run this code
and you might be thinking, oh well
this is already at the end of your
code so the file would have been
closed by default anyways you're
correct but the file actually closes
as soon as my with statement is
done running and so my my file is
actually closed before we hit line
13 unlike this file up here where if
I didn't include this line right
here it wouldn't automatically close
so the with open uh function in
regards to files is super useful for
keeping things clean and making
sure that you don't have just like
loose hanging files open in your
algorithm floating around out there.
Let me just wrap this
video up with another quick
thing. So I can still
open up that file again.
I can say file 2 n equals
by or sorry equals open
and then let's grab
output 2.txt and I can
still read through this.
I can still say print
file to again dot read lines and
that will print out the output
hello and goodbye in a list
like we like we learned so we're
still totally able to do that and
good practice would be to file
to again dot close once we're
done with it so that's kind of the
width open in a nutshell Thanks
for watching this content video.